Chair, Martin Lewis · Editor, Marcus Herbert

Founder, Martin Lewis · Editor-in-Chief, Marcus Herbert

Get our **free weekly** Money Tips email!
-----------------------------------------

Grab the latest deals, guides, tips 'n' tricks directly from Martin and the MSE team. Don't miss out

Search MoneySavingExpert

Search

Close search bar

1. [MoneySavingExpert.com](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/ "MoneySavingExpert.com")
2. [Site](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/ "Site")

MSE weekly email

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------

For all the latest deals, guides and loopholes simply sign up today – it's spam-free!

MoneySavingExpert.com
=====================

Privacy Policy
--------------

Updated 20 May 2024

Share Share Close

**Here at MoneySavingExpert.com we're all about cutting your costs and fighting your corner. Your privacy is important to us, and we want you to be confident that the information you give us when using our site is safe and secure. This Privacy Policy explains how we will use your personal information when you use our Site including to give you a better, more personalised MSE experience, so please read it carefully.**

This Privacy Policy explains how we use your personal information, including the following:

* where we collect your personal information from;
* what personal information we collect;
* how we use your personal information;
* who your personal information is shared with; and
* the rights and choices you have when it comes to your personal information

**Updated:** 20 May 2024

* #### [1\. What this Privacy Policy covers](#accordion-content-0775836371-0 "1.	What this Privacy Policy covers")
    
    This is the Privacy Policy for the MoneySavingExpert.com website, our related apps, the tools on our website, our social media content and our Forum (the "**Site**").
    
    MoneySavingExpert.com Limited (referred to in this policy as "**we**", "**us**" or "**our**") is the "controller" under data protection laws. Where we're processing your personal information in relation to our content and/or Site, we're controller of your personal information.
    
    Where we refer to "personal information" in this Privacy Policy, we mean information which constitutes "personal data" under the UK version of the General Data Protection Regulation (the "UK GDPR"). This can be any information that directly identifies you (such as your name or email address), but also information that identifies you indirectly or would identify you when pieced together with other information (such as your age, gender, demographic information, IP address, and cookie identifiers/other unique online identifiers).
    
    The main purposes we collect and process your personal information are to: show you relevant content and to improve your experience on the Site; provide you with the Site and the other services you request from us, such as our Clubs services (together the "**Services**"); communicate with you directly when you've agreed to it, or when the law allows us to do this.
    
    To operate the MoneySaving tools on our Site we may sometimes need to share your personal information with other businesses, including other members of our Group (see section 6 below). They'll be responsible for how they process your personal information. They're discussed in section 7.1 of this Privacy Policy and in section 9 of our [Terms](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/terms-conditions/).
    
    Our Site contains external links to other websites that aren't subject to this Privacy Policy. Please do read our [Terms](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/terms-conditions/) for further information on external links, as well as the terms and conditions and privacy policy of any website you give your personal information to, as you'll be bound by them. We're not liable for anything that happens if you use them.
    
    Our Privacy Policy explains:
    
    * [The personal information we collect](#personalinfo);
    * [How and why we collect and use your personal information](#howandwhy);
    * [Why we process your personal information](#process);
    * [When and why we'll share your personal information to Moneysupermarket Group, or to other organisations](#disclose);
    * [The rights and choices you've when it comes to your personal information](#rightsandchoices);
    * [Why we use cookies](#cookies);
    * [The steps we take to ensure your information is kept secure and confidential](#steps);
    * [How long we'll hold your information for](#howlong); and
    
* #### [2\. Personal information we collect](#accordion-content-0775836371-1 "2.	Personal information we collect")
    
    The information we collect will depend on how you're using our Site and Services and should usually be clear to you at the time we collect it, for example, for MSE's Money Tips email, we'll ask for an email address. If you're using one of our tools (Cheap Energy Club, Credit Club, Broadband Unbundled, MSE Compare+ Car Insurance, the MoneySavingExpert App, and eligibility tools, together the "**MSE Tools**") we may, depending on the tool, need to get a range of information, such as your name, marital status, benefit entitlements, income and bank account details. Some of the MSE Tools use technology provided by MONY Group companies (formerly known as Moneysupermarket Group) as detailed in section 6 below. We may also use cookies and other tracking technology to collect information about your online browsing behaviour and any devices you've used to access our Site.
    
* #### [3\. How we collect and use your personal information](#accordion-content-0775836371-2 "3.	How we collect and use your personal information")
    
    We collect and use your personal information to allow you to interact with the Site. This includes, without limitation, the following:
    
    **3.1. MSE's Money Tips email**
    
    When you register to receive MSE's Money Tips email we'll use your email address to send you MSE's Money Tips email. This is usually weekly, but on occasion we may send a special edition when we've something really important to share with you – this doesn't happen very often.
    
    **3.2. Product application forms**
    
    When you request certain products or Services via application forms on our Site we'll use your personal information so that we can manage your request. If we need to pass your personal information to someone else to meet your request, we'll make it clear at the time you give us your personal information.
    
    **3.3. MSE Tools**
    
    **3.3.1. Cheap Energy Club**
    
    As part of the Cheap Energy Club service, we'll ask you for certain personal information when you register. We'll save your information to allow us to provide regular energy comparison services based on price savings as part of our comparison service. This will include your name, address, email address, current energy supplier and energy usage and where applicable, application information, to enable you to quickly switch energy suppliers, you've consented to this. 
    
    Cheap Energy Club's energy comparison services are provided by MONY Group companies MoneySupermarket.com and Decision Technologies, who act as independent data controllers alongside us. Our comparison service performs regular background comparisons. We resubmit your information to MoneySupermarket.com to do this and use Decision Technologies to host your energy price comparison enquiry and results.
    
    Where you've provided consent for us to contact you, we will:
    
    * Regularly let you know when you could be on a better tariff based on price savings (for our comparison service);
    * Let you know when your fixed tariff is ending, together with the potential tariffs and related savings available to you;
    * Send you reminders to keep your personal information and preferences up to date (see section 9.1.5); and
    * Let you know about news, energy saving information and energy deals regarding the possibility of saving you money or energy market updates such as price rises; and
    * Keep you informed of new features we introduce into Cheap Energy Club.
    
    We carry out this processing to meet our obligations to you under the Cheap Energy Club service to ensure you're not overpaying on your energy bills. See section 4 below for more information.
    
    If you choose to switch energy suppliers, MoneySupermarket.com will collect your energy switch application information and pass it on to the energy supplier you're being switched to. We will also save your information (as detailed in this Privacy Policy). This may also include sensitive information which data protection laws call 'special category data' if you tell us that you've special needs. We rely on your explicit consent to collect and process this 'special category data'. Where applicable, MoneySupermarket.com will also process all cashback due in connection with switches. See MoneySupermarket.com's cashback T&Cs and [MoneySupermarket.com's privacy policy](https://www.moneysupermarket.com/legal/privacy-policy/) for how it looks after your personal information.  
    
    MoneySupermarket.com and Decision Technologies will only hold your personal information for so long as is reasonable in relation to providing you with energy comparison services and/or switching energy suppliers and/or in cases in which you've provided your consent (which you may withdraw at any time). See section 6 below for further details on sharing your personal information with MONY Group companies (formerly known as MoneySupermarket Group).
    
    We'll contact you:
    
    * To welcome you to Cheap Energy Club;
    * To communicate with you at your request via live chat to troubleshoot any energy comparison or switch issues you may have; 
    * To communicate with you at your request to help with logging in to Cheap Energy Club (for example, to reset your password);
    * To alert you to changes to our services (such as changes to our [Terms](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/terms-conditions/));
    * In connection with an application to switch your energy supplier (including in connection with cashback due to you under the switch if this is applicable to you);
    
    **3.3.2. Credit Club**
    
    As part of the Credit Club service we'll ask you for certain information when you register. This will include your email address and mobile number. 
    
    We'll contact you:
    
    * To welcome you to the club and provide personalised credit information and products that match your credit profile that are likely to save you money;
    * To confirm you're who you say you are as part of our identity authentication process;
    * To communicate with you at your request to help with logging in to Credit Club (for example, to reset your password);
    * To personalise and enhance your experience within Credit Club (such as presenting content in the best way for you);
    * To alert you to changes to our services (for example, changes to our [Terms](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/terms-conditions/)); and
    * To alert you when your Affordability Score, Eligibility Score, as well as your TransUnion Credit Score and your TransUnion Credit Report have been updated
    
    We carry out this processing on the basis of our contract with you. If you've also given us consent, we'll also contact you to let you know about consumer news, other MoneySaving tips, products and exclusives which we think you may be interested in.
    
    **3.3.3. Eligibility tools**
    
    We use the personal information you give when you submit an eligibility checker request to let you know your percentage chances of successfully obtaining a credit card or loan.
    
    When you use our **eligibility checker services** a credit report will be generated by **carrying out a 'soft' credit check**. We do not carry out these checks. Instead, we pass your personal information to our trusted service provider **HD Decisions** – **an Experian business** (**HD**) or certain of our panel of lenders (detailed in section 7 below), which will generate these checks with their chosen credit reference agencies. The 'soft' credit checks will be used by HD and the other partners mentioned below, to match against those partners' own lending criteria. This information will be used to let you know your percentage chances of successfully obtaining a credit card or loan. Note that your credit report will not be provided to you directly and we will not receive it either.
    
    If you give us your email address, we'll also send you a confirmation email of your results so that you've a record of them. For more details on how we share data with third parties when we conduct eligibility checks, see section 6.
    
    **3.3.4. MSE Compare+ Car Insurance tool**
    
    Our MSE Compare+ Car Insurance comparison tool is provided by MoneySupermarket.com.
    
    MoneySupermarket.com will collect and save your personal information to be able to return results. This may also include sensitive information which data protection laws call 'special category data', if you tell it that you've a criminal conviction or provide details of your medical history. MoneySupermarket.com relies on your explicit consent to collect and process this 'special category data' and requires this data to be able to display insurance quotes. As part of this tool, if you run a quote, MoneySupermarket.com will send you an automatic email with your top quotes so that you can easily refer back to them. MoneySupermarket.com will not use your data for any other marketing purposes. See the MoneySupermarket.com privacy policy for further details on how your personal information is used.
    
    We do not process or save the personal information collected in the MSE Compare+ Car Insurance tool unless you sign up to receive an email renewal reminder from us when it is time to switch again. In this case we will save your name, email address and renewal date to fulfil your request. See the MoneySupermarket.com privacy policy for further details on how your personal information is used.
    
    See also section 6 below.
    
    **3.3.5. The MoneySavingExpert App**
    
    Once you've downloaded the MoneySavingExpert App you'll have the option to create an account which allows you to access enhanced tools and features to personalise and tailor your content. Without an account, you'll still be able to access the full site and most tools, as well as the ChatGPT API to ask questions which it derives answers for, by using our Site. The ChatGPT API should be used in accordance with our Terms which makes clear that no personal information should be shared by you or collected by us in using the ChatGPT API.
    
    Without an account, you'll also still be able to access content from our website, but the content won't be personalised. If you choose to create an account, we'll ask you for certain personal information, such as your name and email address, and ask you to choose a password for your account. If you create an account you can choose to use certain MSE Tools (such as Hot Topics, Bill Buster and the Regular Payments Detective) by connecting your bank account within your App account using a secure third party called TrueLayer (please see section 7.1.3 for further details). If you consent for us to save the results of your use of the MSE Tools and/or tools exclusive to the App, we can use these together with your account information to provide further personalised guidance and MoneySaving tips ("**MSE App Enhanced Content**").
    
    **3.4. Forum**
    
    We collect limited personal information to enable you to post on our Forum: your email and IP address(es), username and password. We use your email address to send you your password to enable you to log in to our Forum and to send you emails if you've chosen to sign up to MSE's Money Tips. We use your email address, IP address(es) and username for admin, troubleshooting and investigatory purposes if required. As set out in the Forum rules which form part of our Terms, no personal information should be shared on our Forum (aside from your username). Consequently, no personal information should be collected on our Forum.
    
    **3.5. Internal reporting, insight and analysis**
    
    We may use your personal information to generate aggregated, anonymised data for the purposes of internal reporting, insight and analytics, enabling us to improve and personalise our Site, the products we offer and search results for our Site. In processing your information for these purposes, we may use Google Analytics. See our [Cookie Policy](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/cookies-qa/) for further information. Where necessary this exercise may be carried out on our behalf by someone else – please see section 7 below.
    
    **3.6. Site personalisation**
    
    We may use your personal information to personalise aspects of our Site, enable your details to be moved across our tools to speed up form filling and for market research. As part of this, we may match your personal information against information that has been collected by someone else. We are always working to make a better Site for you and using your personal information in this way helps us to do this. It also means that if you've given us permission, any communication we send to you is appropriate for your needs.
    
    **3.7. Contacting you**
    
    We may use your personal information to:
    
    **3.7.1.** Respond to any communications that you've directed at us;
    
    **3.7.2.** Invite you to take part in polls and other market research activities carried out by us and on our behalf. Any feedback you provide will only be used to improve our Site and will not be published. It is up to you whether you want to take part in these activities; or
    
    **3.7.3.** Award you a prize if you've won a competition we're running.
    
    If you're providing us with another person's personal information you should first ask them to read this Privacy Policy and our [Terms](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/terms-conditions/). By giving us personal information about another person you're confirming that they have given you permission to provide the personal information to us and that they understand how their personal information will be used.
    
* #### [4\. Why do we process your personal information?](#accordion-content-0775836371-3 "4.	Why do we process your personal information?")
    
    We'll only collect and use your personal information (as described in sections 2 and 3) in accordance with data protection laws. Our legal grounds for processing your personal information in the ways described in this Privacy Policy are as follows:
    
    * **Performance of a contract** – To provide you with the services you sign up to. For example, when you register to use Cheap Energy Club, we'll (i) save your information for the purposes of allowing us to compare energy deals, (ii) use your personal information to do regular background comparisons so that we know when to switch or make available to you information on energy tariffs based on your chosen savings trigger and preferences and (iii) match the top tariffs to you based on your preferences.  

    * **Consent** – We'll only collect and process your personal information where necessary and, if we're relying on consent for such processing, if you've consented for us to do so, for example, when you register to receive MSE's Money Tips email, or download the MoneySavingExpert App and create an account. For Cheap Energy Club, we'll only send you communications if you've confirmed that you're happy to receive them. These communications may be provided: to update you on energy savings, including when you can save money; to provide energy saving news; to let you know about energy deals; and to let you know when your energy tariff is ending.  

    * **Legitimate Interests** – We may use and process some of your personal information where we've sensible and legitimate business grounds for doing so. Under European privacy laws there is a concept of _"legitimate interests"_ as a justification for processing your personal information. Our legitimate interests for processing your personal information are:  
          
        * To enable us to provide our services, including the MSE Tools;
        * To enable you to use our Forum and ensure it operates smoothly, we may use your personal information to make sure our Forum operates without disruption or abuse and to enforce our Terms; and
        * To improve our Site. We may use your personal information to undertake demographic segmentation and generate profiling information to help us understand what you might be interested in and for market research. We are always working to make a better Site for you and using your personal information in this way helps us to do this
    
    You've a right to object to our use of your personal information for these legitimate interests, including a right to object to profiling by us (see section 8 below).
    
    * **Legal obligation** – We may be required to process your personal information to comply with a legal obligation on us; for example, an obligation to disclose the information to a court or regulator, governmental, compliance or law enforcement agency, or in connection with legal proceedings; or to prevent fraud and money laundering, which might involve disclosure to a fraud prevention agency. We may also be required to process certain personal information about you to respond to (and verify we are able to respond to) a data subject rights request that you have submitted. 
    
* #### [5\. Use of children's personal information](#accordion-content-0775836371-4 "5.	Use of children's personal information")
    
    We don't knowingly collect or store any personal information about children under the age of 16.
    
* #### [6\. Sharing your personal information with the rest of the MONY Group](#accordion-content-0775836371-5 "6.	Sharing your personal information with the rest of the MONY Group")
    
    We are part of the MONY Group (formerly called the Moneysupermarket Group) comprising: Moneysupermarket.com Limited, Decision Technologies, Quidco, CYTI, Travelsupermarket, icelolly and Podium, which all operate in the UK. MoneySavingExpert.com's specific way of operating is governed by the [Editorial Code](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/editorial-code/). 
    
    **6.1.** The MONY Group operates a shared IT infrastructure which includes shared technologies, platforms, systems and tools. Your data may be shared with other MONY Group entities as a result of this shared infrastructure. We implement shared security measures on this system which comply with data protection law and ensure that there are adequate internal controls to keep the data secure. This information might be used and analysed to improve products and services across the Group. However, the different entities will not use your personal information to send you direct marketing or target you with advertising, unless you have separately given your specific consent to this. 
    
    **6.2.** Your information may also be shared where you are using an MSE Tool that uses technology provided by a Group company or as otherwise permitted under the Editorial Code, for example (i), the Cheap Energy Club comparison service is provided by MoneySupermarket.com and Decision Technologies and; (ii) the MSE Compare+ Car Insurance tool is provided by MoneySupermarket.com. By submitting your personal information to either of these services, you understand it will be passed to other MONY Group companies. Please read the rest of our Privacy Policy about how your personal information will be used and the [MoneySupermarket.com privacy policy](https://www.moneysupermarket.com/legal/privacy-policy/) and the [Decision Technologies privacy policy](https://decision.tech/privacy-policy/).
    
* #### [7\. Sharing your personal information with others](#accordion-content-0775836371-6 "7.	Sharing your personal information with others")
    
    We may share your personal information with:
    
    **7.1. Our technical partners** – For the purposes described in sections 3.3 to 3.6 and 6 above, and for the purposes of providing certain services and enabling your interaction with the Site, such as your use of MSE Tools. These include:
    
    **7.1.1.** TransUnion International UK Limited ("**TransUnion**") – We operate Credit Club in conjunction with UK credit reference agency TransUnion and Qualifi Solutions ("**Qualifi**"). When you submit your details to Credit Club, they will be passed to TransUnion and Qualifi and we will let you know every time your TransUnion Credit Score or TransUnion Credit Report has been updated.
    
    TransUnion may share the information it collects from us with fraud prevention agencies including Cifas, which will use it to prevent fraud and money-laundering and to verify your identity. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information.
    
    If fraud is detected, you could be refused certain services, finance or employment. Further details of how your information will be used by TransUnion and these fraud prevention agencies can be obtained by writing to TransUnion at TransUnion International UK Limited, One Park Lane, West Yorkshire, LS3 1EP.
    
    TransUnion and other organisations may access and use the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies from other countries.
    
    More information about your rights in relation to the personal information TransUnion holds can be found in the 'Your rights to how we use your personal information' section of its privacy policy.
    
    For further information about how your details will be used by TransUnion, please see the rest of our Privacy Policy and [TransUnion's privacy policy](https://www.transunion.co.uk/legal/privacy-centre/pc-bureau);
    
    **7.1.2.** HD Decisions, an Experian business ("**HD**") and certain other of our panel members including Capital One Bank (Europe) plc (**Capital One**), Shawbrook Bank Limited (**Shawbrook**), Admiral Financial Services Limited (**Admiral**), Hastings Financial Services Limited (**Hastings**), Mitsubishi HC Capital UK PLC Trading as Novuna Consumer Finance (**Novuna**), Lendable Operations Limited (**Lendable**), Oakbrook Finance Limited (**Oakbrook**) and Zopa Bank Limited (**Zopa**) (together, "**Panel Members**"), in order to make our eligibility checker service available to you. We operate the eligibility tools in conjunction with HD, and these Panel Members. They, in turn, partner with the following UK credit reference agencies: TransUnion International UK Limited ("**TransUnion**"), Equifax Limited ("**Equifax**") and Experian from time to time.
    
    We'll use the personal information you submit to enable your interaction with our eligibility tools. If you use our eligibility tools a credit report will be generated by carrying out a 'soft' credit check. 'Soft' credit checks allow you to get quotes without affecting your creditworthiness. The 'soft' credit checks will be used by Panel Members to match against their lending criteria and HD to match against other suppliers' lending criteria. The Panel Members' and HD's information is then used to let you know your percentage chances of successfully obtaining a credit card or loan. Your credit report will not be provided to you directly and we'll not receive it either.
    
    When you submit your details, you're giving permission to HD and the Panel Members mentioned above to share those details with TransUnion, Equifax and/or Experian. To find out more about how your personal information will be used, please see the rest of this Privacy Policy, [HD's terms and conditions](https://termsandconditions.hdd2.co.uk/) and the terms and conditions and/or privacy policies of our Panel Members. Please also see the [Credit Reference Agency Information Notice](https://www.experian.co.uk/crain/index.html).
    
    Our technical partners will not be allowed to use your personal information for their own marketing purposes unless you separately consent to receive marketing from them.
    
    **7.1.3.** TrueLayer Limited (www.truelayer.com) ("TrueLayer") – Where you agree to us being able to 'read-only' access your bank account data, we use TrueLayer, a secure open banking provider. Please see section 9.5.2 of our Terms and Conditions for detailed information on TrueLayer. By signing up to this service you will need to accept its [terms of service](https://truelayer.com/enduser_tos) and your personal information will be processed in accordance with its [privacy policy](https://truelayer.com/privacy).
    
    **7.2.** If required or permitted to do so by law;
    
    **7.3.** If required to do so by any court, the Financial Conduct Authority or any other applicable regulatory, compliance, governmental or law enforcement agency;
    
    **7.4.** If necessary in connection with legal proceedings or potential legal proceedings;
    
    **7.5.** If ownership of all or part of our Site is transferred, in which case any purchaser would only be entitled to use that information in a way consistent with this Privacy Policy; and
    
    **7.6.** In line with our own [Terms](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/terms-conditions/), which incorporate our [Forum rules](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/forum-faqs/) (in particular regarding reporting offending Forum users to their ISP or to the authorities if their actions appear to amount to a crime).
    
* #### [8\. How you can amend your preferences](#accordion-content-0775836371-7 "8.	How you can amend your preferences")
    
    All emails or other forms of communication directly from us to you will include clear instructions on how to unsubscribe. Plus, if you don't want to be contacted by us anymore, you can email [DataRequest@moneysavingexpert.com](mailto:datarequest@moneysavingexpert.com). Section 9 below also sets out your other information rights.
    
* #### [9\. Your information rights and responsibilities](#accordion-content-0775836371-8 "9.	Your information rights and responsibilities")
    
    **9.1.** You've certain rights under data protection legislation in relation to the personal information we hold about you:
    
    **9.1.1. Right to access** – The right to a copy of the personal information we hold about you. We'll ask you to describe the information you require, as well as letting us know about any other email addresses you've used on our Site, to enable us to trace your personal information. Depending on the nature of your request, we may also ask you for your full name, your date of birth and your full address and documents to allow us to verify your identity. Requests for copies of your personal information will be dealt with within one month, unless your request is complicated or if you've made a large number of requests. In these circumstances it may take us longer to deal with your request, in which case we'll let you know;
    
    **9.1.2. Right to correct** – The right to have your personal information rectified if it is inaccurate or incomplete. Requests for us to correct your personal information will be dealt with within one month, unless your request is complicated or if you've made a large number of requests. In these circumstances it may take us longer to deal with your request, in which case we'll let you know. If we believe that your personal information is accurate, we'll let you know that we won't be amending your personal information and why;  
    
    **9.1.3.** **Right to erasure of your information** – The right to request that we delete or remove your personal information from our systems. Data protection laws give exceptions to this right which, if applicable, we'll explain in our response to you; 
    
    **9.1.4.** **Right to restrict our use of your information** – In some circumstances you can 'block' us from using your personal information or limit the way in which we can use it;
    
    **9.1.5.** **Right to data portability** – The right to request that we move, copy or transfer your personal information; and
    
    **9.1.6.** **Right to object** – The right to object to our use of your personal information including where we use it for our legitimate interests, or where we use your personal information to carry out profiling to inform our market research and user demographics. If you raise an objection we'll stop processing your personal information unless an exemption under UK data protection law applies, in which case we'll let you know why we're continuing to process your personal information. Some of the MSE Tools give you the option to hear from us by email about tips, news, and relevant MoneySaving products and exclusives. You've the right to object to our processing of your personal information in this way.
    
    **9.2.** To make enquiries, exercise any of your rights set out in this Privacy Policy and/or make a complaint please contact [DataRequest@moneysavingexpert.com](mailto:DataRequest@moneysavingexpert.com) or write to the Data Protection Officer at MoneySavingExpert.com at MONY Group House, St. David's Park, Ewloe, Flintshire, CH5 3UZ.  
    
    **9.3.** If you're not satisfied with the way any complaint you make in relation to your personal information is handled by us then you may be able to refer your complaint to the relevant data protection regulator. In the UK, this is the Information Commissioner's Office.
    
* #### [10\. Cookies](#accordion-content-0775836371-9 "10. Cookies")
    
    **10.1.** We use cookies (not the type you eat, but files which are sent by us to your computer or other devices), web beacons, pixel tags and tracking technology to help improve the functionality and performance of our Site.
    
    **10.2.** The information coming from our use of cookies will be aggregated to provide statistical information about the usage of our Site. However, we don't use any information derived from cookies, nor any IP addresses we collect, to identify any individual user of our Site.
    
    **10.3.** Some third-party technology we use (such as embedded videos, social sharing) also drop cookies to improve your experience on their sites.
    
    **10.4.** For details on what cookies we use, information on how to stop them being stored or how to delete ones already stored, read our [Cookie Policy](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/cookies-qa/).
    
* #### [11\. Where we store your personal information](#accordion-content-0775836371-10 "11.	Where we store your personal information")
    
    **11.1.** Keeping information about you secure is very important to us so we store and process your personal information in accordance with the high standards required under data protection laws. It might sometimes be necessary for us or our suppliers to transfer your personal information outside of the UK either within the European Economic Area (EEA); or outside of the EEA. However, we will only transfer your personal information out of the UK to a jurisdiction which has not been determined by the UK Government as being "adequate" for data protection purposes if we have put in place appropriate safeguards and protections as stated under UK law, for example by the use of a data-transfer agreement incorporating either the UK's international data transfer agreement or addendum, which have been approved by the UK Government in accordance with the UK GDPR and Data Protection Act 2018.
    
* #### [12\. How long do we keep your personal information?](#accordion-content-0775836371-11 "12.	How long do we keep your personal information?")
    
    We'll only hold your personal information on our systems for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy and/or in cases in which you've provided your consent (which you may withdraw at any time), or until you request it is deleted (unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law).
    
    Generally, you can expect us to keep your personal information while you use the Site or MSE Tools (or have used MSE Tools recently, for example, if you've recently switched to a new energy supplier using our Cheap Energy Club comparison), or regularly open MSE's Money Tips email. Where you've applied for or purchased products or services via the Site we'll need to keep your personal information for longer for accounting purposes – up to seven (7) years following the date on which it is provided to us. If, having registered for any of our services, you don't use them for a reasonable time (which may vary depending on the service(s) you've registered for) we may contact you to ensure you're still happy to receive communications from us.
    
    Even if you delete, or ask us to delete your personal information it may persist on back-up or archival media for legal, tax or regulatory purposes.
    
* #### [13\. How to contact us](#accordion-content-0775836371-12 "13.	How to contact us")
    
    Our Data Protection Officer is MONY Group's Chief Risk Officer.
    
    If you've any queries relating to our use of your personal information or any other related data protection questions, please contact us at [DataRequest@moneysavingexpert.com](mailto:datarequest@moneysavingexpert.com) or write to us at MoneySavingExpert.com Limited, at MONY Group House, St. David's Park, Ewloe, Flintshire, CH5 3UZ.
    
* #### [14\. Changes](#accordion-content-0775836371-13 "14. Changes")
    
    We reserve the right to amend or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and any changes will be published on the Site. The date of the most recent revision will appear on this page. If we make significant changes to this policy, we may also notify you by other means such as sending you an email. If you do not agree with any changes please do not continue to use the Site or App.

**Effective as of:** 20 May 2024

##### Share this guide

**Spotted out of date info/broken links? Email:** [brokenlink@moneysavingexpert.com](mailto:brokenlink@moneysavingexpert.com)

* ### [Sainsbury's Bank customer? You're set to be moved to NatWest next year – here's what's happening](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/news/2024/06/sainsburys-loan-credit-card-natwest/)
    
    20 June 2024

    If you have a credit card, loan or savings with Sainsbury's Bank, you could be moved to NatWest next year as part of a deal between the two banks – but it's still early days and there's NO change right now.
    
* ### [Base rate held at 5.25% again – but with a possible cut in August, what does it mean for your mortgage and savings?](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/news/2024/06/bank-of-england-base-rate-held/)
    
    20 June 2024

    The Bank of England has held the base rate at 5.25% for the seventh time in a row – but with some economists and traders still predicting a rate cut in August, there could be a knock on impact on mortgage and savings rates.
    
* ### [Get £50 off energy standing charges with EDF's new discounted Price Cap tariff](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/news/2024/06/edf-energy-launches-new-tracker-tariff/)
    
    18 June 2024

    The new EDF Ensure tracker tariff is effectively a discounted version of the Price Cap that will be £50 cheaper over the year – and it does this by lowering standing charges, not unit rates.
    
* ### [Warning: Five holiday booking scams to watch out for as £12 million a year lost to travel fraud](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/news/2024/06/holiday-booking-scams-warning/)
    
    18 June 2024

    If you're booking your next holiday, watch out for fake deals, clone websites and bogus cancellations, as criminals are using a variety of sophisticated methods to trick holidaymakers out of their money.
    
* ### [Airports hike 'kiss and fly' charges to as much as £7 for a five-minute drop-off – how to beat them](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/news/2024/06/airport-drop-off-charges/)
    
    18 June 2024

    Seven major airports across the UK upped the cost of dropping off passengers over the last year, a MoneySavingExpert investigation reveals – and five now charge a whopping £6 or more to let someone out at the kerb.

* ### [Martin Lewis: Don't shop at Zara before you go to Spain, Greece, France or Italy](https://blog.moneysavingexpert.com/2014/05/buy-zara-clothes-at-a-fraction-of-the-cost-and-get-a-flight-thrown-in/)
    
    18 June 2024

    Update 17 July 2017: We tend to think since Brexit that the pound’s weaker than it has been for decades. While somewhat true against the dollar, against the euro it’s only a tad worse now than when I first wrote this in 2014.   The logic of this blog stands just as strongly now. On the Spanish-English website...
    
* ### [Martin Lewis: Get £100s of credit back from your energy firm – it's all about the Direct Debit cycle…](https://blog.moneysavingexpert.com/2024/05/martin-lewis--stop-the-rip-off---get-p100s-credit-back-p100s-fro/)
    
    28 May 2024

    In this in-depth blog, Martin Lewis talks you through how to get £100s of credit back from your energy firm. It's all about the Direct Debit cycle…
    
* ### [Martin Lewis: An important warning to every employee in the UK](https://blog.moneysavingexpert.com/2021/04/martin-lewis--an-important-warning-to-every-employee-in-the-uk/)
    
    14 May 2024

* ### [Martin Lewis: Employed aged under 22, or any age earning under £10,000? How to get a hidden pay rise](https://blog.moneysavingexpert.com/2021/04/employed-aged-under-22--or-any-age-earning-under-p10-000--how-to/)
    
    14 May 2024

* ### [Martin Lewis: We can't ignore the impact of money issues on people's mental health – here's what we're trying to do about it](https://blog.moneysavingexpert.com/2024/05/martin-lewis--we-can-t-ignore-the-impact-of-money-issues-on-peop/)
    
    3 May 2024

* ### [How to multi-destination holiday like a MoneySaver](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/deals/deals-hunter/2024/06/how-to-multi-destination-holiday-like-a-moneysaver/)
    
    13 June 2024

* ### [How to keep fit for FREE](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/deals/deals-hunter/2024/01/how-to-keep-fit-for-free/)
    
    4 June 2024

* ### [Get 'paid' to walk using free apps](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/deals/deals-hunter/2019/05/get-paid-to-walk/)
    
    24 May 2024

* ### [How to get free pet food and treat coupons for cats or dogs](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/deals/deals-hunter/2024/05/how-to-get-free-pet-food-and-treat-coupons/)
    
    23 May 2024

* ### [FREE £17 organic and vegan sunscreen mini at selected O2 stores](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/deals/deals-hunter/2024/05/free-17-organic-and-vegan-sunscreen/)
    
    16 May 2024

MSE tools & calculators

### 

Clever ways to **calculate** your finances 

      [

Credit Card Eligibility

See which cards are likely to accept you

Tool](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/eligibility/credit-cards/search/)

      [

Loans Eligibility

See which loans you've the best chance of getting

Tool](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/eligibility/loans-calculator/search/)

      [

MSE App

Get MSE on your Apple or Android phone

Tool](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/the-moneysavingexpert-app/)

      [

Broadband Unbundled

Compare broadband deals & save

Tool](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/compare-broadband-deals/)

      [

Mortgage best buys

Compares thousands of mortgages

Tool](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/mortgages/best-buys/)

      [

Mortgage Calculator

Eight calcs for all your mortgage sums

Tool](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/mortgages/mortgage-rate-calculator/)

Show all Show less

#### How this site works

We think it's important you understand the strengths and limitations of the site. We're a journalistic website and aim to provide the best MoneySaving guides, tips, tools and techniques, but can't guarantee to be perfect, so do note you use the information at your own risk and we can't accept liability if things go wrong.  

* This info does not constitute financial advice, always do your own research on top to ensure it's right for your specific circumstances and remember we focus on rates not service.  
    
* We don't as a general policy investigate the solvency of companies mentioned (how likely they are to go bust), but there is a risk any company can struggle and it's rarely made public until it's too late (see the [Section 75](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/reclaim/section75-protect-your-purchases/) guide for protection tips).
* Do note, while we always aim to give you accurate product info at the point of publication, unfortunately price and terms of products and deals can always be changed by the provider afterwards, so double check first.  
    
* We often link to other websites, but we can't be responsible for their content.  
    
* Always remember anyone can post on the MSE forums, so it can be very different from our opinion.

MoneySavingExpert.com is part of the MONY Group (formerly called the MoneySupermarket Group), but is entirely editorially independent. Its stance of putting consumers first is protected and enshrined in the legally binding [MSE Editorial Code](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/editorial-code/).

Please read the [Full Terms & Conditions,](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/terms-conditions/) [Privacy Policy](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/privacy-policy/), [Cookie Policy](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/cookies-qa/), [How this site is financed](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/moneysavingexpert-finance/) and [MSE's Editorial Code](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/site/editorial-code/).

#### More tools from MoneySavingExpert

[### Credit Card & Loans Eligibility Calculator

Shows which top cards and loans you're most likely to get.](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/eligibility/)

[### Income Tax Calculator

Find out how much income you keep and how much tax you pay.](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/tax-calculator/)

[### Ultimate Mortgage Calculator

Eight calculators to compare mortgages, incl how much overpaying could save you](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/mortgages/mortgage-rate-calculator/)

[### Cheap Mobile Finder

Easily compare the top mobile phone and Sim only deals.](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/cheap-mobile-finder/)

[### Credit Club

Turbo boost your credit chances and get your free TransUnion credit report.](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/creditclub/)

[### Compare Travel Money

Our TravelMoneyMax tool compares 15+ bureaux to max your holiday cash.](https://travelmoney.moneysavingexpert.com/)

[### Compare Broadband Deals

Our Broadband Unbundled tool finds the cheapest broadband, phone and TV.](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/compare-broadband-deals/)

[### Car Insurance Compare+

Our tool gives you tips and tricks to help you get cheaper car insurance quotes.](https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/car-insurance-compareplus/)

Martin Lewis is a registered trade mark belonging to Martin S Lewis.  

Get our **free weekly** Money Tips email!

Grab the latest deals, guides, tips 'n' tricks directly from Martin and the MSE team. Don't miss out
